[{"question":"<p><strong>What volume of substance 'y' with a density of 8.4 x 10<sup>2<\/sup> kgm<sup>-3<\/sup> will have the same mass as 4.2m<sup>3<\/sup> of substance 'x' whose density is 7.2 x 10<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>kgm<sup>-3<\/sup> ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.4m<sup>3<\/sup>","3.6m<sup>3<\/sup>","4.9m<sup>3<\/sup>","5.8m<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A pressure cooker saves both time and fuel in cooking because inside the cooker the _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Boiling point of water is raised","The temperature is evenly distributed","Pressure is constant","Volume of steam varies"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following phenomenon CANNOT be explained by the molecular theory of matter&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Expansion","Radiation","Conduction","Evaporation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pairs illustrate isotopy ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oxygen and ozone","But-1-ene and But-2-ene","Hydrogen and deuterium","Ortho-hydrogen and para hydrogen"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A gas occupying an initial volume of 2dm<sup>3<\/sup> is heated and allowed to expand to 6dm<sup>3<\/sup> at constant pressure. The ratio of the initial absolute temperature to the final absolute temperature is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3:1","1:3","2:1","1:2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the changes determine the spontaneity of a chemical reaction ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Volume of the rectants","Free energy of the system","Entropy of the system","Enthalpy of the system"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is NOT correct of group (VII) elements ? They<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are diatomic","Are good oxidizing agent","Are highly electronegative","Have relatively low ionization potentials"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the minimum volume oxygen required for the complete combustion of a mixture of 20cm<sup>3<\/sup> of CO and 20cm<sup>3<\/sup> of H<sub>2<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>","options":["10cm<sup>3<\/sup>","20cm<sup>3<\/sup>","40cm<sup>3<\/sup>","80cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the reactions of marble with dilute HCI is fastest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5g of marble lump at 50<sup>\u00b0<\/sup>C","5g of marble lump at 25<sup>\u00b0<\/sup>C","5g of marble powder at 50<sup>\u00b0<\/sup>C","5g of marble powder at 25<sup>\u00b0<\/sup>C"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 12 and 9 are the atomic numbers of elements P and Q respectively, the interatomic bond between these element is&nbsp; _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Co-ordinate","Neutral","Covalent","Ionic"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>All the following statements are false about sodium chloride in the solid state except________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It exists as aggregate of ions","It conducts electric circuit","It exists as discrete molecules","Its ions are linked by metallic bonds"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The abnormally high boiling point of water is due to ________<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["It high molecular mass","The presence of metallic bond","The presence of hydrogen bonds","The presence of covalent bonds"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The rate of diffusion of a gas R is inversely proportional to the square root of it density this statement is synonymous with______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Composition of mass","Graham's law of diffusion","General gas law","Gay Lusaac's law"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the volume of oxygen required to burn completely 20cm of carbon (II) Oxide<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10cm<sup>3<\/sup>","20cm<sup>3<\/sup>","30cm<sup>3<\/sup>","40cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One mole of substance contains the _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Atomic number of particles","Faraday's number of particles","Avogardro's number of particles","Quantum number of particles"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>These are factors affecting rate of chemical reaction, except_____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Surface area","Catalyst","Nature of the reactants","Activation energy."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The unit of rate of chemical reaction is _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mol dm<sup>-3<\/sup>s","mol<sup>-1<\/sup>s<sup>-1<\/sup>","mol<sup>-1<\/sup>","smol<sup>1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the main use of the crucible in the laboratory ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Filtering precipitates","Igniting precipitates","Drying Salts","Condensing vapour"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Methane, ethane, propane, butane and pentane are five simplest______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alkenes","Alkynes","Alkanes","Olefins"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a system at equilibrium is disturbed, the equilibrium adjusts itself in such a way as to cancel our or annul the effect. This is ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The law of chemical equilibrium","Le Chatelier's principle","Law of enthalpy","Law of entropy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reaction between KOH and NO<sub>2<\/sub> produces water and ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["KNO<sub>2<\/sub>","KNO<sub>3<\/sub>","HNO<sub>3<\/sub>","KNO<sub>3<\/sub>and KNO<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these methods is employed in the separation of hydrocarbons in petroleum ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Catalytic cracking","Polymerization","Fractional distillation","Hydrogenation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One advantage of alcohol over mercury as a thermometric fluid that ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It expands more uniformly than mercury","It is a better conductor of heat and than mercury","It has a lower freezing point than mercury","It has a lower specific heat capacity"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A labile salt dissolved in water can be separated by <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Evaporation","Crystallization","Filtration","Steam distillation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The atomicity of ozone is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The nucleus of an atom is composed of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Positively charged protons","Negatively charged electrons","Neutrons","Protons and neutrons"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following are metals except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Silicon","Tin","Lead","Chromium"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The half-life of an element is 12hrs. If the initial mass. 50g, what mass will be left after 2 days ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.125g","6.25g","12.5g","25g"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which brass of the following is an alloy of aluminium<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brass","Bronze","Gelena","Magnaliium"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd compound<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Toluene","Phenol","Ethanol","Benzene"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is correct<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The randomness of molecules is less in a liquid than in a solid","Diffusion does not occur in solids at all temperatures","The intermolecular forces are weaker in liquids than in solids","The pressure of a gas is  the combined force with which the gas molecules collide with one another in a container"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following zones is NOT part of a non-luminous Bunsen flame ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Blue zone","Unburnt","Bright yellow luminous zone","Non-luminous zone"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a secondary air pollutant ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Particular dust","Sulphur (IV) oxide","Ozone","Chlorofluorocarbons"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Ammonia can be obtained from ammonium tetraoxosulphate (VI) by heating it with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dilute HCI","Conc. H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>","CuSO<sub>4<\/sub>","NaOH"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds is soapless detergent ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["C<sub>12<\/sub>H<sub>25<\/sub>OSO<sub>3<\/sub>Na","C<sub>17<\/sub>H<sub>25<\/sub>COONa","C<sub>6<\/sub>H<sub>5<\/sub>OH","C<sub>4<\/sub>H<sub>9<\/sub>COOC<sub>2<\/sub>H<sub>5<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following properties of radiations from radioactive substances is FALSE<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gamma rays are deflected by a magnetic field","Alpha particle is a helium nucleus","Beta rays are streams of high energy electrons","Beta rays are strongly deflected by a magnetic field."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The emission of electrons due to the application of heat is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["High field emission","Cold cathode emission","Thermionic emission","Secondary emission"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is\/are true of liquids and gases ? I. Both are fluids II. Their particles are in constant motion. III. Both are compressible IV. Boyle's law is applicable to both<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I and II only","II only","I and III only","IV only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Ethanoic acid is found in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sour milk","Sour palm wine","Lemons","Crude oil"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Graphite occurs naturally as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dolomite","Limonite","Plumbago","Chalcago"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Carbon (II) oxide is poisonous to many animals because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It combines with oxygen from the air","It combines reversibly with haemoglobin","It combines irreversibly with haemoglobin","It forms oxalic acid in the lungs"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The purest form of silica is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Flint","Opal","Quartz","ZnSiO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds of the tin is a strong reducing agent ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["SnCl<sub>2<\/sub>","SnCl<sub>4<\/sub>","SnO<sub>2<\/sub>","SnH<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds of the tin is a strong reducing agent ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["SnCl<sub>2<\/sub>","SnCl<sub>4<\/sub>","SnO<sub>2<\/sub>","SnH<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following will not form complexes with zinc ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ammonia","Trioxonitrate(V)ions","Cyanide ions","Halide ions"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Methane and parafin wax are very similar in many ways. The main reason why they differ chemically is that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["One is a gas and one is a solid","On complete combustion their products differ","One is a Hydrocarbon and one is carbohydrate","They come from different sources"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many moles of oxygen are produced when 20 moles of water are decomposed ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","10","15","20"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A measure of the degree of disorderliness in a chemical system is know as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Activation energy","Enthalpy","Entropy","Free energy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A brand of ink containing cobalt (II) chloride and Iron (II) ions can be separated into its various components by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fractional crystallization","Fractional distillation","Sublimation","Chromatography"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The pollution from petroleum spillage in rivers and lakes can best be dispersed by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pouring detergents","Passing of ship through the sea","Pouring organic solvents","Evaporation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Water is poured over a white solid and a colourless neutral gas is evolved, which burns with a sooty flame. The white solid is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Calcium","Calcium oxide","Calcium carbide","Sodium peroxide"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The complete oxidation of butan-2-ol yields<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Butane","Butanal","Butan-2 one","Butanoic acid"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main constituents of petroleum are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alkanes","Alkynes","Gases","Hydrocarbons"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which pH value indicates a basic solution ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","3","0","-1"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Oxidation is the process of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gain of electrons","Loss of electrons","Gain of hydrogen","Loss of oxygen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following factors does NOT affect rate of a chemical reaction between non-gaseous reactants ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Temperature of reaction mixture","Presence of catalyst","Surface area of reactants","Weight of the products"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A mixture of 12g of carbon and 64g of sulphur is heated until reaction is complete and none of the reactants is left over. What mass of carbon (IV) sulphide is formed ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15g","15.2","76g","760g"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a petroleum product?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["candles","nylon","plastics","diesel oil"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following obeys ohm's laws ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Glass","Diode","All electrolytes","All metals"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is the best known semi-conductor ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carbon","Selenium","Gallium arsenide","Germanium"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following law is an application of the law of conservation of energy ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Maxwell's law","Lenz's law","Faraday's law","Fleming's left hand rule"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following are limitations of Bohr's model, EXCEPT<br><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The stability of the atom","Variation of the atomic radius","The line spectra of hydrogen","The experiment determination of the atomic radius"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>X-rays were discovered by&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Isaac Newton","Michael Faraday","Sir J.J. Thompson","W.Roentgen"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a physical change ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The bubbling of chlorine into water","The passing of steam over heated iron","The burning of substances in air","The dissolution of sodium chloride in water"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A mixture of oil and water can be easily separated by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Paper chromatography","Evaporation to dryness","Using a separating funnel","Fractional distillation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Bronze is a\/an<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Metal","Compound","Mixture","Element"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>To separate a mixture of benzene, ethanol and water use<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Filtration","Decantation","Simple distillation","Fractional distillation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Hydrogen&nbsp; forms two oxides. In the first oxide, 2g of hydrogen combine with 16g of oxygen. In the second oxide, 2g of hydrogen combine with 32g of oxygen. What law is illustrated ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The law of constant proportion","The law of conservation of matter","The law of multiple proportion","The law of reciprocal proportion"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lead forms two chlorides. The ratio of chloride atoms in the two chlorides is 1:2. If the mass of chlorine in the second chloride is 42.0g, find the mass of chlorine in the first compound<\/strong><\/p>","options":["71g","72g","21g","73g"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is heavier, 0.2mol SO<sub>2<\/sub> or 0.2mol CO<sub>2<\/sub>? [S = 32, O = 16, C = 12].<\/strong><\/p>","options":["SO<sub>2<\/sub> is heavier by 4g","CO<sub>2<\/sub> is heavier by 44g","SO<sub>2<\/sub> is heavier by 0.4g","CO<sub>2<\/sub> is heavier by 40g"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A gas jar of air was placed on top of a gas jar of nitrogen IV oxide. After sometime, a uniform colour was seen throughout both gas jars. What process has occured ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Evaporation","Oxidation","Decomposition","Diffusion"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following atoms A,B,C and D would readily form an ion with a charge of 2+?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mass No: 12                                Atomic No: 6","Mass No:  16                               Atomic No: 8","Mass No:  24                              Atomic No:12","Mass No:  31                               Atomic No:15"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ion X<sup>+<\/sup>contains 23 particles in the nucleus and 10 electrons outside the nucleus outside the nucleus. What does the nucleus of the ion contain ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Protons: 10                                        Neutrons: 13","Protons: 11                                        Neutrons: 12","Protons: 12                                        Neutrons: 11","Protons: 13                                        Neutrons: 10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following are properties of carbon in the form of diamond ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Conductivity: nil           Melting point:-101<sup>0<\/sup>C","Conductivity: nil           Melting point: 119<sup>0<\/sup>C","Conductivity: nil          Melting point:  3500<sup>0<\/sup>C","Conductivity: good      Melting point: 26000<sup>0<\/sup>C"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The non-luminous Bunsen flame has the following characteristics <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">except<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The flame is hotter","The flame is cleaner","The flame enters the tube to consume any incoming fuel","Only three zones can be seen in the flame"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Water of crystallization is responsible for&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shapes of crystals","Melting of salts","For purity of crystals","Boiling point of salts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The substance which loses its water of crystalization on exposure to air is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Deliquescent","Efflorescent","Hygroscopic","Crystalline"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>To determine the solubility of a salt in the laboratory, you need a\/an<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Saturated solution of the salt","Unsaturated solution of the salt","Supersaturated solution of the salt","Homogenous solution of the salt"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major water pollutant is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Spillage of oil","Pesticide","Detergent","Sewage"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following acids is monobasic<\/strong><\/p>","options":["H<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>","H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>3<\/sub>","CH<sub>3<\/sub>COOH","H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following substances is not a polymer<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nylon","Polyethane","Propane","Starch"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The preferential discharge of sodium during the electrolysis of brine using mercury as cathode is due to one of the following<\/strong><\/p>","options":["High concentration of Na<sup>+<\/sup>","Na<sup>+<\/sup> is lower than H<sup>+<\/sup> in the electrochemical series","Discharge of sodium as the amalgam requires less energy","Concentration of H<sup>+<\/sup> is higher"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following gases can be collected by the upward displacement of air ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NO","H<sub>2<\/sub>","NH<sub>3<\/sub>","Cl<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cycloalkane with the molecular formula C<sub>5<\/sub>H<sub>10<\/sub> has<\/strong><\/p>","options":["One isomer","Two isomers","Three isomers","Four isomers"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The electronic configuration of an element is 1s<sup>2<\/sup>2s<sup>2<\/sup>2p<sup>6<\/sup>3s<sup>2<\/sup>3p<sup>3<\/sup><\/strong>.&nbsp;<strong>How many unpaired electrons are there in the element ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","4","3","2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following&nbsp; ions is a pollutant in drinking water even ini trace amounts<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ca<sup>2+<\/sup>","Hg<sup>2+<\/sup>","Mg<sup>2+<\/sup>","Fe<sup>2+<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following represents the types of bonding present in ammonium chloride molecule ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ionic only","Covalent only","Ionic and dative covalent","Dative covalent only"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The air around a petroleum refinery is most likely to contain<\/strong><\/p>","options":["CO<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>2<\/sub>&N<sub>2<\/sub>O","CO<sub>2<\/sub>CO&N<sub>2<\/sub>O","SO<sub>2<\/sub>CO&NO<sub>2<\/sub>","PH<sub>3<\/sub>H<sub>2<\/sub>O&CO<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following salts can be melted with decomposition<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>","CaCO<sub>3<\/sub>","MgCO<sub>3<\/sub>","ZnCO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><b>The number of neutrons contained in the nucleus of <sup>238<\/sup><sub>92<\/sub>U is<\/b><\/p>","options":["92","146","238","330"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sample of orange juice is found to have a PH of 3.80. Which is the concentration of the hydroxide ion in the juice ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6x10<sub>-4<\/sub>","6.3x10<sub>11<\/sub>","6.3x10<sub>-4<\/sub>","1.6x10<sub>11<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Water for town supply is chlorinated to make it free from<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bad odour","Bacteria","Temporary harness","Permanent harness"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is formed when maltose reacts with concentrated tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Coal tar","Charcoal","Toxic fumes","Carbon(IV)oxide."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following metals will liberate hydrogen from steam ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Copper","Iron","Lead","Mercury"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The fraction of crude oil used as jet fuel is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Refinery","Diesel oil","Kerosene","Gasoline"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many grams of bromine will be required to completely react with 10g of propyne&nbsp;[C = 12, H = 1, Br = 80]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20g","40g","60g","80g."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"}]